We have to make sure we have appropriate communications
about current and potential threats to keep awareness high.
We could even encourage friendly competition between
departments to spot the most fishing attempts.
We can offer friendly reminders like a little
squishy stress ball that says lock your computer.
There are also automatic systems that lock the computer automatically.
When you step away.
It is important to make sure we get positive feedback about our training,
ensuring it is appropriate and understood.
Make sure the organization's leaders understand the importance of training and
working to promote and improve the
information security environment of the organization
and provide the opportunity for personnel to practice
what they've learned with exercises and simulations.
Occasionally send simulated fishing emails for example and
give them positive feedback for reporting it.
Depending on the organization's culture and risk profile
awareness training should be a positive experience for everyone
and not punitive unless it is absolutely necessary.